campbell seventh-day adventist church we
are so happy that you have joined us
again today um this is the sabbath this
is the day the lord has made and we are
happy and we are rejoicing in it
um this is actually our sabbath school
time and so um those of you who have
been with us for the last uh several
weeks you know that we've been going
through the 2300 day prophecy
um and we've had uh pastor patel tara
patel and his brother adam helping us go
through uh this prophecy step by step
and it has been such a huge blessing and
last week we said hey do you guys want
to do some question and answer so if
there's any gaps um in your
understanding from the things that
they've covered we're going to try to
answer those questions today so i'm
excited to get clarification for all of
you even for myself um so that we can
just know this prophecy and be able to
share it um in an amazing way with our
friends with our family and this just
helps ground us as we are seventh-day
adventists it helps us to have a firm
foundation um that we can stand on for
who we are um as a church and as a
people so we just praise god for this
prophecy and the understanding that the
holy spirit and god are giving us to go
deeper
as you can see we um have a different
look today because we are not in our and
our normal uh place that we record in
california we're actually in virginia um
and we came here uh because um i
mentioned last week my one of my really
dear friends passed away
two weeks ago and um and so her funeral
was this week on wednesday and so we
flew out um on sunday um and we have
been able uh to be here with family and
also just minister to the family that
that lost my dear friend you know i just
want to say a few things about her it's
like i the the funeral was so amazing i
mean of course we were all very sad you
know she was only 43 years old and you
know lost her battle to cancer um after
six years um but her life was so amazing
in those 43 years
um that
it was you were inspired at the funeral
the you know i don't know anyone who
left there that wasn't inspired to just
want to go serve and help others like
her
her life was serving people and
ministering to people through service
and so she was an amazing cook she
started her own vegan catering um
company and so she catered large events
but then she also helped those who
were less fortunate and giving them uh
food um for free or you know just doing
all types of things to help them and
also teaching them about healthy living
at the same time and that's how she did
evangelism she also started projects
which i'm going to talk about
next because i'd love for you guys to be
a part of it but
i remember when she called me a few
years ago and said hey i'm cancelling
christmas for my family i want to my
family has everything they need um and
so let's let's um get together with many
of her other friends and let's buy gifts
for those children who are in need and
she had a wish list from each child we
could choose those things that they were
wanting we could purchase and um those
things for these children that didn't
have
um you know family or means to be able
to do that for them and so that's just a
little bit of who she was i could go on
and on i have to tell you her funeral
was probably
three and a half hours long and that was
not just people that was people sharing
about her service ministry of her life
um just in her short 43 years and so
she was an amazing woman um i want to
and i'm going to put this in the chat so
if you guys want to also donate to this
ministry that she supported um because
it's called the children's home.net and
the children's home
is in catonsville maryland it's a
residential care facility that provides
both long and short uh term service to
youth 13 to 21 years of age who have
experienced abuse neglect violence
abandonment
and they are just needing supervised
care and so this is the ministry that
she worked very closely with um they
have and you can read more about what
she did for them because they've done
like a special thing on their website
when they heard she passed and so i'm
going to put their um their their
website and the chat and if you want to
give uh to this ministry just to honor
her legacy um and to help people who are
children and young adults who are in
need um you'll be able to do that so i
was encouraged to just want to do more
service for others and i'm just
encouraging everybody else that your
christianity becomes real and becomes
alive and amazing and exciting
when you're helping other people so
that's the that's what i learned from
her life and i wanted you to partake of
that as well yeah her philosophy was
really
based on getting outside of the walls of
the church right and ministering to
people right um you know ministering to
real needs yes and um i think that
philosophy
is one that really should be carried
into every church
we gotta understand that church is not
it's not so much what we do
inside the building it's what happens
outside the walls of the building right
what happens outside the walls of the
building will determine
the
you know we'll determine what happens
the blessings we receive inside the
walls of the building
some people are asking me to repeat the
website and i'm going to put it in there
it's
thechildrenshome.net and i'm going to
put it in the chat when we when we get
started um
yeah
so yeah you're right i have to say this
people are probably saying you don't
have a message on your shirt today and i
do it's just simple it's the cross it's
simple but very profound life-changing
and that's what our christianity is all
about what jesus did for us on the cross
so
yeah
so um
we are going to be
uh
really today is really like a freestyle
day if you will where we're just going
to be
you know maybe touching on some a few
principles a few thoughts um
regarding the 2300 day prophecy its
importance
um and overview
but we're mostly focused on your
questions yes that's what we want to get
we want to we want to answer your
questions so we have covered a lot
uh over the last
six seven years this is our eighth week
this is our eighth week and so we want
to help you um if there's any area i
know there's been people that have said
in the chat like as they're as they're
as you guys would be talking like okay
that that lost me a little bit okay this
you know either it was going too fast at
times we tried tried to do my job not
perfectly all the time but tried to do
my job to help slow things down
and so this is where you guys get to ask
your questions um and
you are really making the sabbath goal
today so they're just here to answer
your questions because last week was an
overview
and if you still have questions which
many of you put up once last week saying
that you had questions that's what we're
going to spend our time doing today
and want to welcome adam
and his brother should join us shortly
um but we're going to say a word of
prayer before all right let's pray
heavenly father
we thank you
for giving us another opportunity to
come together and to fellowship lord
to study to answer questions
and we pray lord that um you would give
us clarity of thought clarity of mind
and again that you would settle
your people in truth lord
um
we we ask that you would pour out your
spirit upon us and grant us a spirit of
understanding
and we just ask this in the precious and
holy name of jesus we pray for those
um who are watching
and um
we just ask lord your blessing upon us
as we study in jesus name we pray amen
amen amen amen
welcome sir
good to be back
praise the lord happy travis
happy sabbath to everyone who is joining
us so
uh the only way we can get your
questions is if you put them in the chat
so
please um those of you who
have questions about the information
that was covered within the last seven
weeks please
post and let us know uh while we're
waiting um oh okay we got one
all right the first one is please
explain what jesus was doing prior to
his move to the most holy place
we'd like to take that one
awesome well i can give it a shot of
them
follow up yeah um
well the bible tells us that
um as soon as he ascended in hebrews 1
he sat down at the right hand of the
father and he was anointed
our high priest
um and according to the type in the old
testament the daily services kind of
gives us the indication
of what christ began to do as soon as he
attended what the high priest would do
in the daily services
is he would spend time ministering
uh with the candlesticks providing oil
to the candlesticks
um
that's a that's a that's a message for
you and i because in revelation chapter
1 jesus is in the midst of the seven
golden candlesticks and when you read
that you understand that these seven
golden candlesticks represents the
church so immediately when he goes to
heaven he's ministering to the church
um he's providing the holy spirit to you
and i so that you and i can reflect the
glory of god as you notice in the book
of acts when jesus went to heaven the
signal
that his anointing was complete was
pentecost we know this because in
leviticus 8 and 9 the high priest when
he was anointed fire came down from
heaven that's exactly what happened in
pentecost christ was anointed high
priest fire comes from heaven and then
there begins a ministry in heaven at the
same time on earth
the people of god have received the oil
to go forward to do the work christ has
also been interceding on our behalf as
the scripture says the altar of instance
makes that really clear he's there to
receive our prayers he's there to
intercede on our behalf and to cleanse
us from all unrighteousness those cold
the power of god's cleansing blood
also then you have the word of god the
table of show bread
christ has been revealing himself you
know what's amazing is that when he
before he went to heaven
the first thing that he did when he
resurrected is he had a bible study with
his disciples
and he began to unveil himself in the
scriptures like never before and when he
goes to when he went to heaven he's been
doing that ever since revealing himself
revealing the word
to us so that we can have a relationship
with him through his word our dynamic
relationship through him to receive the
life of christ
i'm getting um some i'm seeing some
comments here about an echo i can hear
it too my ear
yeah um do you think it's your
headphones let me take it off and we'll
see
okay can you hear me
go ahead
are you speaking
actually i was muted okay
okay how is this
i'll keep talking and then just get more
feedback
okay
i can't you can still hear it yeah
so i don't think it was the the headsets
no i don't think it was either
but i hope i answered the question
pastor i don't know if you want to jump
in
while the echo is being kind of
addressed
all right
um so
uh
let me know if you guys are still
hearing feedback
um the way that i would answer this
question is along with what um brother
adam just shared
uh
we need headphones yeah
okay
so along with uh what uh brother adam
just shared
um
last week i preached a sermon on the
vaccine
and what we talked about what i talked
about in that sermon was was really very
simple that
there are two phases to christ's
ministry
um and both phases involve an
administration of the vaccine
the vaccine is his blood
the first part of christ's work the
first
part of that
administration of the vaccine
is to
put us in remission of sins
remission of sins
does not mean that you are cured from
sin
none of us can say that we are cured
from sin
we are only in remission what does that
mean it can come back at any time
it can come back unexpectedly but it can
come back
when
the final phase of christ's work
is not
just about the remission of sins but
about the curing of sin once and for all
so this is the work that the
investigative judgment points to it is
the final putting away of sin
which is why the scapegoat comes into
play
because here you have the the sins being
ultimately put on a skateboard and sent
out into a desolate place
and that is what in essence concluded
the jewish year
so
what is the difference between christ's
holy place ministry and his most holy
place ministry it is a difference
between the remission of sins and then
the curing of sin
okay adam if you want to jump in i'm
going to mute so i will mute
when uh
amen praise the lord so
i just want to make somebody ask the
question too pastor and i think
it's a good question it says so the work
he began
prior to his move to the most holy place
is completed
let me let me just make that this plain
so when the bible describes the two
phases of ministry
um when he goes into the most holy place
to
complete the judgment work it does not
mean that he ceases to intercede on
behalf of his people
because even if you look at the most
holy place work if we want to be
technical
the incense the golden censor was
brought into the most holy place
so the intercession work never stops
um and if you look at the seven golden
candlesticks for instance the seventh
candlestick which is the church of
laodicea
that church needs more ministering than
ever
than any other church probably you know
what i mean so christ will never stop
his intercession work on behalf of his
people
what the phase or the most holy place
work really emphasizes is what the
pastor is saying the completion
of the administration of the vaccine
whereby you know christ for the first
time in history
for the first time in history
he will have a church living on this
earth that has been cured
and that's the amazing goal of the
ministry of christ in the most holy
place and this is why the message we
have is so important so i hope that
answers the question uh of what christ
has been doing and what he is doing
again he's still ministering on our
behalf he's still to intercede
um but
now that we know he's in the most holy
place we're in the fourth quarter it's
crunch time he's finishing up the work
and there's a work for us to do in
cooperation with the high priest
we should be doing ex the same thing
that the people were doing on the day of
atonement afflicting our souls uh so
that we can cooperate with him in this
cleansing work
hopefully everybody could hear me okay
amen amen there's another question
um
i like how you say that this is the
fourth quarter i mean that's just the
picture that helps people to see how
serious the times we are living in now
um somebody asked in hebrews 9 3 where
paul mentions the most holy place the
hebrew words were mentioned as hagiai
hagion um i couldn't locate hacky eye is
that the singular
or hagio
you know what i think
that's a really good question and my
brother's going to be joining soon he's
going to be able to answer that probably
more correctly because he took the greek
and all that um but what i do is when i
go to blue letter bible it it says hagia
but when you play it it it's actually it
says hagion and when you play it he
pronounces it as hagia
so i believe it's in the plural
um
so just i would also try to get the
pronunciation of it because not all when
you look at the greek and you try to
read it using your english it's not
pronounced that way all the time um
so i believe it's in the plural but just
to get more of a satisfactory answer uh
maybe we can table that one
uh
until my brother gets back
um
okay sorry about it there no that's okay
that's okay um okay we have another
question that says will you please
explain what's going on in daniel 9 26
and the people of the prince who is to
come shall destroy the city and the
sanctuary the end of it shall be
with
a flood and up to the end
of verse 26
or just explain okay in the line 26
um so i'll i'll take this one
um
i mean
well we can jump in and share back and
forth with it um
so in daniel 9 26
the people of the prince that shall come
the the prince that's being spoken about
here
we did this a few weeks back how we
showed that
in these verses you have a
a uh
there are parallel events going on
okay
um
there's a a b a b between daniel 9 26
and daniel 9 27
so the people of the prince that shall
come remember jesus
just before he was going to the cross
remember these words that he said
the prince of this world cometh
and has nothing in me
right he's talking about satan
and ultimately when you look at the the
parallels we're looking at in daniel 2
daniel 7 and daniel 8.
it's this same little horn
but in its pagan
and ultimately papal phase is being
spoken about in daniel 9.
particularly
initially it's pagan phase so we know
that rome destroyed the temple
uh and destroyed the city
we know that rome that satan worked
through rome
in the book of revelation chapter 12.
remember where the the woman is pregnant
with the child with the male child and
the dragon stands before her to devour
her this is speaking of uh number one
satan himself but number two
it's speaking of rome satan is working
through rome and that's what we find in
daniel 2 daniel 7 daniel 8
it's primarily
rome but then it will be pig paper rome
following along in the steps of rome so
when it talks about until the end we're
talking about the consummation of all
things
okay
this is in line with daniel 2
daniel 2
um
tells us
that the consummation
is when the kingdoms of this world are
consumed by the stone cut out without
hands
daniel 7 the consummation
is when the judgment sits uh after the
little horn does his thing the judgment
sits to take away his kingdom and to
consume it unto the end
the same in daniel 8 the same in daniel
chapter 9
daniel 9 is speaking about this little
horn
but in its pagan and people face
amen i think that's an excellent answer
okay um and yes someone texted there are
questions that have been overlooked and
it's they're not being overlooked
they're just flowing in so quickly
so we're going back i know there was uh
one
uh question
that
but i like the way they worded it they
said how did christians determine and i
like that they said christians because
they didn't say seventh day adventists
but i'll get to that but how did the
christians determine that 1844 was the
year that jesus moved to the most holy
place the reason why i like that
question is because
you know there's this false
theory or understanding that seventh-day
adventists are the only ones that came
to this
understanding this date and this
prophecy when the christian world at
that time
came
to the same conclusion um and so
yeah answer
how did they how did the christian world
come to that conclusion
so either one of you
i'll just i'll try and start here but
praise the lord i i love that point as
well that it was a christian thing that
you know christians from all different
denominations
came to this day from all over the world
and
they didn't even know each other which
was amazing um
anyhow just by studying the book of
daniel as we have been doing for the
past couple of weeks uh in particular
the 2300 day prophecy in daniel 8 14
seeing the correlation between daniel 8
and daniel 9 when you understand that
these chapters are related and daniel
fainted and and daniel ayton didn't get
an understanding of what the 2300 days
was gabriel comes back in daniel 9 to
give the explanation of the mod a which
was the portion of the vision he did not
understand
once you begin to see those things then
you understand wait a second this 2 300
days has a beginning
and gabriel's telling us the beginning
point and it's this 70-week prophecy
and then
it's clear in daniel 9 24-25 from the
commandment
to going forth to rebuild and restore
jerusalem and then when you take that
commandment of artaxerxes in 457
and you understand that the 70 week
prophecy
has to be a day for a year it cannot be
a literal prophecy or a literal day
because it doesn't lead to jesus so once
you understand these principles
the bible then is clear with showing us
that the 2 300 days starting with 457
has to reach an endpoint
and according to daniel 8 14
that's when the sanctuary is cleansed
and when you do the calculations from
457 2300 days
you end up in 1844
and so this conclusion was uh people
were coming to this conclusion again
from all different denominations from
all over the world and it was based on
the study in daniel 8 and 9. this what
we've been doing for the past couple of
weeks
yeah i think it's uh it's important to
note here
that it wasn't that
this
teaching spread by being passed from
william miller to another person
and to another person and that's how it
spread
people were simultaneously studying this
prophecy
independent of one another denominations
independent of one another
and they all came
to the same conclusion unanimously
so
this
is a sign that this was the holy spirit
at work
so that's just a point i i think is
important for us to understand when
people say
advent seventh-day adventists came up
with this date um that is uh
pretty much specifically incorrect
okay
um real quick someone's asking how did
you get art how did the christian world
get at that time 10
22 1844 specifically
i think they're wanting you guys to go
through
the math of the timeline a little bit
well the the specific date of october
22nd
1844 was used based on the jewish
calendar of the day of atonement
um
which i think is pretty amazing
if you think about it i'm just thinking
about it right now because they at first
set the date as the coming of the lord
um and they thought jesus was coming to
this earth
and of all days they picked that day of
atonement
um but the day of atonement was the day
of judgment
you know where the sanctuary would be
definitely cleanse the sanctuary not on
earth but in heaven so they chose the
date based on i can't i can't remember
the the the set of the jews that they
choose the calendar i want to say
carotide
yeah
they chose that for october 20 22
1844. so
the people who studied this prophecy
they were
detailed to the t
i mean they they made sure all the t's
were crossed eyes were dotted when it
came down to the exact specifications of
this prophecy
um and that's what makes it so
powerful because these things can be
checked and verified
questions could be asked about that and
these things and you'll see in the end
it's so solid
and this is what uh just another
evidence of why it's so convincing
yes another question is will the
righteous dead and the wicked dead be
judged in the investigative judgment
so there are two judgments that are
described
in
[Music]
the book of revelation
the first one is the judgment of the
righteous
the last judgment is the judgment of the
wicked
okay so
the judgment of the righteous is a good
thing
right we want to be in that judgment
um
that's why the bible says in daniel 7
that judgment was given unto the saints
or on behalf of the saints
that is a good thing
again when people hear the word judgment
they often think
um that this is
a scary thing you know what i'm saying
like oh you're telling me that i'm gonna
go through
no that's a good thing because god is
judging on our behalf he he is acting as
our defense attorney if you will
the second judgment is the judgment of
the wicked that's what happens during
the 1000 years the millennium where the
bible says that judgment
is given unto the saints
they are going to have access
for the fact for 1 000 years judgment is
given unto them they're going to be
judging the wicked they're going to be
judging those who are lost they're going
to be looking at the record as to why
they are lost and at the end of the 1000
years
when the wicked dead are brought to life
to face their judgment
they have to know why they are being
cast into the lake of fire
before they are cast into the lake of
fire
right so they're not in the lake of fire
and then taken out of the lake of fire a
judgment is given to them and then
they're cast back into the lake of fire
no before their sentence is actually
executed
they are
they are brought to judgment
and this is what happens at the end of
the millennium the end of the 1000 years
so i don't know if you want to add to
that adam
no amen i mean i would encourage you to
read i think john 5 and um revelation 20
especially revelation 20 it separates
the two resurrections
um
first thessalonians chapter 4 verse 16.
if we pass away we're resting in jesus
we want to be a part of the first
resurrection
um
the wicked will be a part of this second
resurrection two resurrections two
separate judgments
right now the only the righteous are
being judged no wicked people are being
judged and if you think about it the
sanctuary is being cleansed
the only sins that make it to the
sanctuary are confessed sins
that's a huge point to remember
only the sins of the righteous are being
reviewed
and that's why jesus is able to come and
pick them up because he's already
determined who's going to come through
who's going to make it and they're going
to get the reward
but god is so just in the second
resurrection read revelation chapter 20.
that's when the wicked the books will be
open for them and they'll see where
they've fallen short and then god will
execute
uh the uh the consequences
amen
yeah god is i just want to throw in here
because i think that
again i think i ended with this last
week but
um
understanding the judgment and that the
judgment is not this scary
god is trying to get you lost thing
is so important for christians and
seventh-day adventists to really
understand because
being ray's seventh-day ad then it's
being fourth generation and just as a
kid just hearing about these things like
literally i feel like
adventist children
grow up in fear not be honest i mean
um you didn't face that you didn't have
that you came into this as an adult um
but just because as a little kid it's
just it sounds scary and if it's not
taught and a lot of times
it's not it's it's not intentional but
it's what usually happens it's not
really taught in a way to show the love
and the mercy of god i'm just going back
to my friend who passed away a couple
weeks ago just knowing her personal
story and being able to talk to her just
days before she passed uh actually a few
weeks before
she passed as well she was just
sharing about
how
she
first of all she told me she was ready
ready to die because god had prepared
her but the way he prepared her is he
gave her
pure forgiveness for those who had hurt
her
he was giving her a spirit of humility
which she you know you know struggled
with acquiring before
god prepared her so it was like so and i
said when i gave a tribute to her in her
at her service i said god healed her and
he sealed her at the same time
and that's why she could confidently say
she was ready because she knew that she
had that she had repented of any sins
and those you know the things that
the holy spirit was working on our heart
to do and this is really and that's just
god's grace and mercy like he kept her
alive long enough
so that she could do that
she had a really bad spell about a month
and a half prior to her passing maybe
two months prior and that
what she what happened with the
forgiveness of humility had not yet
happened so he kept her alive for like
another two months to give her time to
be able to experience that and so i'm
just saying that to say that you know
that's something we all have to go
through but that's god's mercy and grace
and that is what this investigative
judgment you know is all about it's not
it's just not god trying to get us lost
basically
that's just he's doing everything to
save us so we shouldn't be afraid of it
yeah
amen i'll add here it's like um
so uh someone had brought up about the
law of liberty which i think is a good
point speak and so do as they
shall be judged by the law of liberty
that is liberty from sin right
that's we want
god calls it the law of liberty for a
reason
and
he wants us to speak and do as they that
shall be judged by that law which is a
good thing
right he wants to redeem us he wants to
fill us he wants to sanctify us
um
he wants to
bring us into a relationship with him
that is um
[Music]
liberating
that's what the vaccine of sin does it
liberates
right and that's why it's called the law
of liberty liberty from the works of
this flesh
liberty from fear liberty from guilt
liberty from all those things
amen i think we we can do a lot better
like what atonte what you're saying
pastor as a people with
teaching the word of god
through the experience of jesus christ
through the lens of christ the
revelation the book of revelation is
supposed to be all about jesus and when
you take christ away from it then it
becomes fearful you know and so is the
law of god i like what's being said here
because the reason why god doesn't want
us to commit adultery it's not because
he doesn't want rules to box us in it's
because adultery brings pain
for the person who commits it for the
spouse
and if you have children then there's a
divorce then there's all kind of issues
because the parent the kids don't have
two parents in the home
and and that's why god put it there
because he wants you to be happy he
wants you to have joy he wants you to be
safe he doesn't want
you to go through pain
so it's a liberty from the penalty and
consequences of sin
he can see that if you go this road
you're gonna suffer and people around
you are gonna suffer so my law is going
to make you happy my law is going to
keep you safe my law is going to bring
you joy you know it's not rules and
regulations and there's going to be a
people in the end of time who love jesus
so much they're going to experience that
relationship on such a level they're not
going to sin no more they're not going
to cause any pain no more uh
even even and i saw a question there
that talks about the sins of ignorance
i believe
that even on the day of atonement when
you look at the the offering that was
made on the day of atonement it was a
sin offering
and i i think that the bible is uh uh
purposeful by choosing the sin offering
the sin offering specifically was for
sins of ignorance um i believe when you
mature in christ the more time you spend
with christ the holy spirit convicts you
of righteousness judgment and and and
sin that you won't be committing those
sins of ignorance you won't be falling
into those same things that you used to
fall into
and god's law will become a joy because
you were truly experienced that this is
making me one with jesus and that's the
whole reason i was created to be unified
with jesus christ and that's true
liberation that's true joy that's true
love
and that's the whole
work of the high priest right now in the
most holy place
hey um i think i've seen a a couple
comments about
what is the 2300 day prophecy you know
ultimately about
as well as um
you know is antiochus epiphanes the
fulfillment of that 20 30 day prophecy
so
um
[Music]
let's
let's talk about that for for a moment
um is antiochus epiphanes
uh the focal point of
the 2300 day prophecy
you want to start it off captain you
want to break that down for us i
don't want to break it down but i can't
say that i do understand i mean because
i had a lot of questions about him when
you guys were doing this part of the
study and i was like who is this dude
and why do we
why do people say you know it's about
him and you know not jesus but you guys
take it away
well i'll give it a shot pastor and then
and then you can
you know tie up loose ends um
but when you look at the prophecies of
daniel they're meant to be compared with
one another the little horn of daniel 7
is the same little horn of daniel 8. the
little horn of daniel 7 comes after
the rise of the roman empire which makes
it
impossible for it to be anti-kiss
epiphanies that's one point um also
antiochus epiphanes was not exceeding
great the bible says in daniel 8
and verse
9 that this little horn would wax
exceeding great that's a problem when
you look at the life of antiochus
epiphanes before that it says the greek
kingdom was very great in verse 8 and in
daniel 8 verse 4 the persian kingdom was
great
so antiochus epiphanes was not greater
than alexander the great he was not
greater than the persian empire he was
one of the least great seleucid kings in
the line of kings that's another point
that we have to make also when you look
at the persecution that antiochus
wrought upon the jews
no historian will back up
it was 2 300 days it's not
historically proven or accurate it was
not 2 300 days so here's what most
people do who
promote antiochus they cut the 2300 days
in half and say it was 11.50 number one
that's not biblical
number two it's not accurate no matter
which way you try to cut and slice it
there's no proof to show that the
persecution was
2300 days another point daniel 8 and
verse
tells us
that i think it's verse 20 yep 23 and at
the latter time of their kingdom when
transgressors are come to the full a
king of
fierce countenance
now it describes the little hornets
fierce countenance now if you look at
your bibles i don't know if we brought
up this point last time but go to
deuteronomy
chapter
i want to say 28
you'll see that phrase
that speaks of fierce countenance
now read deuteronomy
versus chapter 28 verses 48
to 53. i'm going to just quickly read at
the end of 48
god is speaking to israel saying this is
what's going to happen if you rebel
against me he says
uh and he shall put a yoke of iron upon
thy neck that's verse 48.
and who's going to do it verse 49 the
lord shall bring a nation
against thee
from the end of the earth a swift uh as
swift as the eagle flying a nation whose
tongue thou shall not understand a
nation of fierce
countenance
now who is this nation of fierce
countenance that's going to come up
against god's people to put a yoke of
iron on their necks if you keep reading
this nation besieges jerusalem and
notice what happens in verse 53 and thou
shalt eat the fruit of thine own body
the flesh of thy sons and of thy
daughters which the lord thy god hath
given thee in the siege and in the
straightness wherewith thine enemy shall
distress thee you can read it on your
own but here's the point this nation of
fierce countenance that comes to bring
an iron yolk think about the iron legs
and the iron teeth
an iron yoke
is a nation of fierce countenance and
then the people under siege eat their
own children this is the siege of
jerusalem in a.d 70 by the roman
power so i said all that to say this the
little horn is being described in daniel
as a roman power a king of fierce
countenance that's another point to make
it clear that it's not antiochus last
and i'm done passive with this
when you read the historical account
of antiochus epiphanes it's in second
maccabees chapter nine that's where you
get the historical account
you'll be shocked i'm i'm giving you the
reference because i want you to read it
second maccabees chapter 9 verses 13 to
you know what antiochus says
when he's on his deathbed
he says that he want he repents
for everything he's done to the jews
and then he says i want to set jerusalem
free
and then he says i want to make the jews
equal citizens with the citizens of
greece and then he says i'm going to
restore all the vessels that i took away
and then i'm gonna pay for their
sacrifices and then he says i want to
become a jew myself and declare the
power of god
does that sound like the antichrist
power in daniel 8 does any of that occur
with this power
absolutely not so we can go on and on
about how it's not on thai kids we i
think that was the first video we made
but those are some solid points to show
that it cannot be antiochus
[Laughter]
i remember all that i just
wasn't prepared to just flow like that
yeah
and i don't know if you just said this
or not but let's add to that that
and welcome um welcome terry
yeah
let's add to that that um
we know that the little horn of daniel 7
is the same little horn of daniel 8. god
is not going to use the same symbol to
confuse us
and throw us off oh this is a different
power especially when we see the
principle of repeat and enlarge in
daniel 2 daniel 7 daniel 8. it is
babylon media persia greece rome what
some people will often do to try to get
to antiochus even in daniel 2
is they divide the medes and the
persians to make them two separate
kingdoms
so they go babylon the medes the
persians and then greece that way they
can say that daniel 70 is greece and
daniel 8 is greece
not so
we also see in daniel chapter 8
that when
the angel asks
how long shall this vision be
we see that it is
not it cannot be days
it has to be years why because the
vision covers the ram
the he goat and then the little horn
the ram
the he go the ram is is uh mido persia
the
goat
is greece
that is already way beyond 2 300 years
the vision that question is asked
the question
involves the entire vision right not a
particular part of it but the entire
vision and this is why
the entire antiochus epiphanes things
just just does not fit
anywhere in this prophecy
it it takes something that is grand and
huge
and
really
brings it down to a very insa like as we
said before who in the world knows about
antiochus epiphanes except the
christians that believe this prophecy is
pointing to him right
it is he is not as great as babylon or
media persia or alexander the great
or the roman empire and so this is
you know and again we've covered this
extensively in our last seven or eight
videos so
uh yeah this is just kind of the cover
that point once again
yeah
and just laugh just another two points
jesus identifies the abomination of
desolation as a roman power matthew 24
verse 15 and for those who espouse
entire kiss you also say antiochus
epiphanes is in daniel 11 31 whereas
where it's clearly listed out there the
abomination of desolation
jesus our lord and savior puts that
power as a roman
power you got to deal with that one
other point i want to make clear because
i think there's confusion about this
where the little horn derives from in
daniel 8 some people say it's from the
horns from the four horns but if you
read the verse it's not from the four
horns that the little horn derives from
and i think that's where the confusion
lies because if it derives from one of
the horns then they say it's a greek
power but it doesn't derive from one of
the four horns look at the verse daniel
8 and verse 9 and out of one of them the
question is what's to them out of one of
them came forth a little horn
just go back to the previous verse the
last thing that's mentioned
is the four winds
of heaven
the four winds of heaven
and if you want to double check your
answers i would plead with you
to go to daniel 11 read verses one two
three four
yep and you'll see the four winds
mentioned again there just to reiterate
the point that it was from one of the
winds that this little horn comes hope
that makes sense
yes but it's
anything you want to you want to add
there
oh sure um just a little historical i
guess thing i can add um
with antiochus epiphanes that view is
based on writings of josephus
and also the book of maccabees
now
josephus was a jewish historian turned
roman basically
and um so that view became popular
because josephus wrote it
um
he
vouches for the view of entitled
epiphanies as well as the book of
maccabees is not clear in the book of
maccabees but the book of maccabees when
recounting the story
of antiochus epiphanes
refers to the term the abomination of
desolation
so
those two are the sources that this view
stands upon
and these are two jewish sources you've
got to ask yourself are these inspired
sources these are extra biblical sources
there are many other things that
josephus has written that are very
problematic when you look at the
writings of josephus he's a good
historian but we're talking about
inspired writings as well as the book of
maccabees
notice that the book of maccabees is not
in your bible not in my standard bible
it did not make it into the canon
however you probably see it in the
catholic bible and
other
uh maybe other christian denominations
just wanted to throw that piece in as
where this foundation of that belief
comes from
so um pastor tarek there was a question
that they both tossed to you that came
up
at the beginning of the program but um
and if that person can repeat their
question or if you guys remember it
perfectly i know it was about the um
the haggy eye and hagion um and i think
i i'm not remembering exactly what the
question i know it was about that and if
it was
plural or plural singular yeah um i
don't know if the person wants to just
type it really quick specifically now
that pastor tarek is here we can get
that question answered
it might take a few seconds that there's
a delay um
all right well we might have to keep
going um let's see okay i don't think i
understood the question i know i didn't
you know why you didn't understand it
because i didn't say it right that's why
you know honestly i mean i'll say i
didn't i didn't quite understand the
question as well what they were asking
okay yeah i know they were talking about
hebrews 9 3
and um
uh if the term haggai hadion is
uh i i i'm not really sure what they
were asking
um
i don't know if they were saying that
they could not find had the eye hacking
on i think they couldn't find hacky eye
which
um
let's see
okay is not singular or okay sorry
they're saying
hebrews 9 3 is haggy on
um
okay is haggy eye the singular or is
hacking the singular
okay is haggy eyes singular is that the
question
yeah is haggy either singular and haggy
on the plural
the way it is written
they're saying hagion is mentioned
several times but not hackyon need more
explanation and you did explain that i
mean i'm but go i i was
before you jump in there i would say
this that
what you're looking for is that
the term is used twice
to describe the most holy place
everywhere else it is used once
right
right it is just hagia
every other book in the book of hebrews
it is it is
singular but in hebrews 9
uh 3 it is used twice
that's the differentiation between a
holy place and most holy place
so when it's used once it's either
talking about the entire sanctuary or
the holy place when it's used twice
which is only done once
that sounds like a dream just now but it
is
used twice only once
that's what it's referring to
yeah
is this person trying to fight it and
want to read it for themselves
yes they were saying
a resource
well just to throw it out there i think
we've talked about it before can
everybody hear me okay
okay good
uh a good resource to to um
to have
is a bible program called lagos or
accordance
and you can get that on your computer
and you can get the original um uh
language language is there and it's a
whole lot easier to read
the flow of greek or the hebrew and that
way it becomes so much more for me it's
a lot better to see you can see the
hagia and hagion right next to it the
words uh together twice mentioned twice
as pastor myers was saying and you can
see it everywhere else where it's
um one
referring to the sanctuary or the holy
place so i would recommend getting logos
or accordance
or you could just get a greek bible
um
an app that i use
let's see if i could just find it real
quick
and it for the new testament it's called
spectrum bible
it has the greek
the greek language
is straight up just written in the greek
and you can see it and you just you know
touch it it'll give you the translation
i'll give you everything it's a parallel
bible too it has different versions as
well so i think that what will help to
answer the question is to find the
proper resources
and that way you can get more intimate
with the text and you can you'll be able
to see it for yourself
and it's always it's always a good thing
yeah i think that's the issue they were
they were having um yeah that's so
that's a good that was a good answer we
have another question which i think is
another great question um
because we're studying this so this is
it's not really a curveball but i think
it
it's
perfect for what you guys are talking
about but
this person said because they realize
the study
just represents um
there we've had um adventist members of
our church and well-known leaders go off
this prophecy go off on this prophecy
and so they were specifically asking and
we and desmond ford is a very well known
person who you know went off on this
prophecy and so this person's wanting to
know where exactly
you know we would have to go deep into
what
exploring exactly every specific of what
he was saying but what is the key point
where he went off that started the
erosion
just before we jump into our question
julian
merlin yes
church craft equals clay
all right
so
where did desmond ford go off
you know i think
it it
i don't know where he began to go off
i just know that he went off in a lot of
places
right i think
i don't think you can pinpoint one
specific thing
um
but that's why it's so important
to understand this is why we have been
going through this prophecy
very slowly and thoroughly and
thoroughly right we haven't done this
hey we're just going to throw this out
one one recording one session
we want to go through this to show you
to show those that are watching
this is not something that was this is
not a belief that was just thrown
together
and this understanding can withstand
you know all the
the scholars who claim this is not so
and all the scholars who
we have been showing in a very
systematic way
how the the entire book of daniel is a
whole
it is not parts and pieces and one thing
is separated from the other the book of
daniel has one message and all the
prophecies
all the prophecies
uh
basically
revolve around that message
right so that is the key that's
why we need to understand the big
picture of this prophecy so that any
attack of it on these other points
whether it's the day four year principle
whether it's antiochus epiphanes he's
the little horn um
whether it's it's actually 100
or 150 days which antiochus epiphanes
did not fulfill either
right so no matter what aspect
your your
this belief is challenged from
you need to be able to answer that
question
from the word of god
do you guys have anything you want to
share with that
man i just want to echo the importance
of what the bible says would line up
online peace at the farm priest of and
especially the visions in daniel just
repeating what the passages said
it's meant to be compared if you don't
line up daniel 2 with daniel 7 with
daniel 8 and 9 and 11 you will be lost
i'm going to give you an example of why
they should be compared when you look at
daniel's so
you will be lost yeah we're not saying
you're going to be lost
we're saying you'll be lost according to
the you'll just be lost in understanding
yeah
thank you for the clarification
yeah you'll be confused you'll come up
with all kind of theories uh very
similar to what desmond ford did you
know um and that's why we started uh the
this whole discussion with building on
that foundation with comparing the
visions it's so important to do that um
when you look at daniel 7 for instance
you have the leopard with four heads and
four wings
there really isn't any explanation
of who the leopard is really and why it
has four heads and four wings
but when you get to daniel 8
and you find out there's a hugo
and that horn is broken and it goes
and it turns into four horns
that goes to the four winds
then you say wait a second that matches
exactly with daniel 7. the four-headed
leopard with the four wings matches with
the four horns that goes to the four
winds
that's an example
that daniel 8 has to be compared with
daniel 7. let me give you another one
in daniel 8
it talks about the ram
who's whose uh uh uh horn
was one horn was bigger than the other
and the the one that was bigger came up
last
that is identical to the bear in daniel
7 whose one side is higher than the
other and so the bible is showing us
that these chapters have to be compared
in order to get a true understanding or
a bigger picture i i always
put it like this
you know they're pieces of a puzzle in
order to see the picture you got to put
all the puzzle pieces together and
that's what the visions are pieces of
the puzzle you put them all together
then you can see clearly the theme
that god wants us to see you can see
clearly
the the the the
the kingdoms
and and what they will do it's amazing
when you study the bible that way
amen i'm just looking at questions
uh which way we can which
which direction we go and next
and maybe some of you guys may have
caught some of these questions that i
missed because they are flowing pretty
quickly
um
so let me uh i jumped in here a little
bit i'm gonna
this is a question in connection with
daniel 2 the clay
and the iron
um and
someone's asking how do we come to the
conclusion that the clay and iron
represents church
and state um so it's really very simple
the iron
is a continuation of the legs of iron
okay a continuation of the legs of iron
which was a roman empire we know that
rome broke down into various nations but
here you have a new element being
introduced and that element is clay and
when you look through the scriptures
clay is used to symbolize the professed
people of god you are the potter we are
the clay
what you have happening
is
that the tolls of daniel describe
a
mingling
of
church
and state which is exactly what happened
in the roman empire after rome fell you
had a religious power rise
right and this religious power
mingled
with
the uh with the kingdoms
uh with the various tribes
of that came out of the roman empire
and ultimately this is what the stone
destroys
at the end of daniel 2. it is this
mingling of church and state which we
see happening down to this very day and
which is what will be necessary to
actually bring about the mark of the
beast to bring about the final
persecution
the
the professed church
connects that's why you read in
revelation chapters
14 and chapter 17 how the kings of the
earth commit fornication with this woman
who is a woman
it's an apostate christian power and she
is connecting with the kings or the
political elements of the world
and so that's how we
uh understand daniel 2
which again
brings us right back to the idea when
you get daniel too and you understand
what daniel 2 is talking about
every other entity at daniel 7 is a is a
amplifying of this church state power
daniel 8 and amplifying of the this is
what this church state power is going to
do daniel 9 the same thing daniel 11 the
same thing
daniel 11 concludes with michael
standing up and coming against this king
of the north
why is that significant
because
jesus is the true king of the north
but here you have a power that is
pretending to be a christian power
pretending to be a christ-like power
which brings us
we talk about checking our work you go
back to revelation 13 you see this beast
with the horns of a lamb
that speaks like a dragon
again the emphasis is this
uh professed christianity that is
actually
apostate and it's mingling with
state powers
this is why the antics epiphany's view
that
god is highlighting some anti-christian
power that is against the bible and
against religion altogether this is what
leads so many people off when it comes
to the mark of the beast when it comes
to the antichrist is because
they see the warning as
a is as the you know the end time enemy
of god's people
is something that is anti-religious and
anti-bible
no
that's what makes it so deceptive
this power professes
christ
hence
one of the main reasons for the
investigative judgment
is god is
look i don't want to really jump into
the sermon i'm about to preach
but i will say this
do y'all remember the story of korra
dayton and byron
all right
here you had cora
who was not trying to rebel
on the fate you know
a rebel against god he was like look we
want to serve god
do you see what i'm saying
we want to serve god and we want to
serve him in the way that we want to
serve him you don't tell us what we can
and can't do
in that chapter god brings a judgment
and moses actually says tomorrow the
lord will show whose or his
and whose aren't
so there is a judgment
that determines
that differentiates between those who
claim christ
versus those who really belong to christ
[Music]
okay i'm done man he's gonna say
somebody in the comments said that
desmond for believe like um and you're
you're just absolutely i can't read
uh that he believed like many other
churches that jesus's work was complete
at the cross i think finished at the
cross if if you wanted to point at like
one of his major
off-ramps or that caused him to go off
on the wrong path i think that would be
a huge beginning
because that's just automatically
getting rid of the sanctuary and the
work of the the heavenly sanctuary
so the one of you want to uh
jump in on that how
was jesus's work finished at the cross
yeah you know when daniel 9 verses and
welcome back bro i think we launched you
and you're back daniel 9
verses
uh 24 tells us the work of christ when
he comes to this earth and how he's
going to
finish the transgression make an end of
sins and to make reconciliation for
iniquity and to bring in everlasting
righteousness
when he came in human flesh he did just
that
he did that as a man walking this earth
he got the victory he kept his father's
commandments because none of us did or
could without his help and so he gained
the victory
so
when he went to heaven now
as a high priest
he's there to offer his victory to us
not only as justification
but sanctification he has imparted the
holy spirit
to us
so that we can now
i'm going to read what the verse says
finish the transgression make an end of
sins make reconciliation of iniquity and
bring in everlasting righteousness so
christ is doing that work right now in
us
and this is what he described in the
visual parable called the sanctuary
in the daily services
in leviticus 1 verse 4 i encourage you
to read that when you put your hand on
the animal your sin was forgiven it was
lifted off of you and put on the lamb
and that service it was called an
atonement
that was the daily service
but then seven months later on the seven
months
later throughout the year on the day of
atonement
all the sins that were lifted off of you
that were brought into the sanctuary on
the day of atonement those sins were
removed it's a different
phase of the ministry so christ is not
only in the business of forgiving your
sins
and taking the burden and guilt from you
he's in the business of changing your
mind
so that you no longer fall into that sin
that was tripping you up that's what the
pastor described in an amazing sermon
last sabbath would be vaccine the blood
of jesus is so powerful and not only
cleanses you from unrighteousness but it
purges your conscience from dead works
to serve the living god hebrews 9 14.
there's power in the blood we sing about
it all the time and that's what he's
doing in the most holy place he's
changing your mind because this is where
the battle begins right here so you are
now in a condition completely cleansed
where you serve him in righteousness and
in truth and that's the work that he's
doing in the most holy place so to
answer your question he finished his
work
on the cross
but now his ministry and the sanctuary
is to finish the work in us he that has
begun
a good work
shall complete it
and i think the verse says that my
brother was on it last week unto the day
of jesus christ so he's going to
complete it right before the coming
before he comes again
amen
um i wish i could show you my screen
right now i got that slide up what adam
just finished saying
um
but there are two verses
that i think is very important
that uh we can go to
and we can understand that there are two
phases
of the atonement process
that jesus
accomplished and is accomplishing
and we can see that he's following the
type that he already gave back in the
book of leviticus if we look at
leviticus
write this verse down leviticus chapter
4 and verse 26
and i'm reading it says and he shall
burn all his fat upon the altar as the
fat of the sacrifice of peace off
and the priest shall make an atonement
for him
concern his sin and it shall be forgiven
him
hear the priest making an atonement and
it shall be forgiven him
atonement forgiven now let's look at
leviticus 16 at the day of atonement and
we're going to look at verse 30.
for on that day shall the priest make an
atonement for you to cleanse you
that you may be clean from all your sins
before the lord
so in the daily service an atonement was
made so that you can be forgiven
in the day of atonement in the yearly
service an atonement was made so that
you can be
cleansed
so there are two phases to the atonement
phase one is forgiveness and phase two
is cleansing you see that in leviticus
chapter four
and leviticus
chapter 16.
yeah uh let me let me add here
um
if jesus finished everything at the
cross
then
he would not need to be doing anything
in heaven
the idea that he finished everything at
the cross is to deny
that he is continuing to work in heaven
and if you deny that he's continuing to
work in heaven you're denying the entire
book of hebrews
so the question i would ask if someone
asked you well you know does it say that
jesus said it is finished at the cross
the question is what was finished at the
cross
not his work
because if his work was finished at the
cross
he would have no need to go be a high
priest
which is work
right in a heavenly sanctuary
he would have no need to be a high
priest he was the lamb
and he his sacrifice was finished
what was finished at the cross was his
sacrifice
right so when people say you know it
sounds once again sanctimonious ah he
did it all at the cross
no he did not do it all at the cross
because he's still doing something right
and this is why so many people find it
hard to grasp
his priestly ministry
because
and here's the you know
i mean just think about this when we
talk about
his most holy place ministry
there's this response oh you're saying
it wasn't all finished at the cross well
let's drop out the most holy place
ministry and just talk about jesus as a
high priest in heaven
you don't hear oh you're saying his work
isn't finished at the cross
it should be the same argument
you should still go what you're saying
jesus
is
interceding on our behalf come on what
are you talking about he finishes work
at the cross you don't hear that you
only hear it
when we start getting into the detail of
what he's actually doing
and people somehow another
feel threatened
because of the word judgment
so
they throw all these things out that
they don't really even understand what
they're saying
yes it's amazing i mean the bible god is
so good he's into parables right and
that's what the sanctuary is it's a
visual parable and he explains the
gospel and in the book of hebrews in the
book of revelation you see christ in the
sanctuary and so if you look at the type
it's extremely clear that when the lamb
dies
on the brazen altar
that's not the end of the sin issue
if you look at the type that's not the
end now here's the blessed hope though
if you as a sinner go to the cross the
brazen altar
and confess your sins you leave there
free of guilt the burden is lifted
but i'm going to quote again hebrews 9
the blood of christ purges the
conscience from dead works to serve the
living god
so when he forgives you he empowers you
the blood changes you something happens
within your life
so that sin that you brought to the
cross now when you leave the cross you
have the power the antidote the vaccine
not to sin again right but what happens
to that sin that you confess
if you look at psalms and and i'm i'm
gonna
explain it this way well let the bible
explain it this way because this this
thing keeps coming up psalms chapter 30
two
look at verse one
uh blessed is he
whose transgression is forgiven now the
word forgiven means to be lifted off
when you confess your sin at that brazen
altar that sin was transferred from you
to the lamb lifted off whose sin is
forgiven whose sin
i'm sorry whose transgression is
forgiven whose sin is covered
now why would it say that your sin is
covered
that word covered means to be hidden
or concealed
read psalms 85 it says the exact same
thing
so look at the type now
when you confess your sin on that lamb
you would leave yes i'm free because the
lamb died for me
but
when you had to lay your hand on that
lamb you had to take the knife and cut
the throat of that lamb and the blood
was collected in the bowl so it was in
essence the blood was covering the sin
the blood was covering the sin
it's hidden it's covered
then the blood that covered the sin
was brought into the sanctuary
now i want you to visualize this the the
priest at times would sprinkle it before
the veil so whenever you walked into the
sanctuary there was blood everywhere
there was blood on the horns and what
did it represent
covered sins
sins that were forgiven
why is it there simply for a record
because what happens is on the day of
atonement those covered sins
will be placed on azazel to bear his
responsibility and so the bible
illustrates the process
of how he oh god the high priest deals
with the sin issue but i just want to
make the point when you confess
and you come to the cross you leave with
that sin separated you from you and the
bible says as far as the east is from
the west i think it's significant the
entrance of the sanctuary was the east
and in the sanctuary was the west so it
literally separates the sin from you as
you're leaving the sanctuary i feel like
i'm running on and on but i just wanted
to make that point
there that there's a process in the type
and when you look at the type you can
see clearly what jesus christ is doing
right now um in the anti-typical day of
atonement and anti-typical service in
the sanctuary
you know i just wanted to say and this
is some this is a comment and a question
actually that a friend sent that
um
i think what happens because i feel like
the seven eight week well the seven
weeks that we've gone extremely slow to
break down this prophecy and explain all
these the different arguments against it
and just you know and be able to expose
them and really explain it i think what
happens with a lot of christians
especially adventists because well with
basically the ones who understand this
prophecy at the most
um is that they don't see the
practicality of understanding this
prophecy at times and so the person said
how is this prophecy
relevant to
a person's daily life i can see the
relevancy clearly especially going
through this study because i see jesus
all throughout this but if you guys want
to just
answer that question
i think people would really appreciate
that
sure i'll say i'll start it off um
what is the relevancy of christ in the
most holy place to our life
well if you know where christ is
and what he's doing then you are aware
of the time that we're living in
it's the time when both temples are
going to be cleansed
not only the temple in heaven but god
wants to clean this temple out
so that's a very good thing to think
about like hey
god is administering the benefits of the
new covenant and he wants to write his
law on our hearts
so we can see that when jesus began his
ministry
pentecost happened
when jesus leaves his ministry latter
reign happened so we understand now
because of his position this is a time
of cleansing there's a time of
afflicting my soul getting serious with
god and preparing for the latter rain
how in the world do i prepare for the
latter rain that's something you can
study and we could definitely talk about
it's also a time of judgment where god
is separating his goats the goats from
the sheep right and it's also a time
where we can see
that the hour of judgment is come
so there is a message that needs to go
forth and be experienced by the people
of god and god wants the world to hear
so when we know that our general is
making a move up there he's given us a
signal and a message that we can follow
his movement down here and to follow his
movements down here is to proclaim and
have the experience of the three angels
messages fear god give him glory for the
hour of his judgment has come worship
him that made heaven and earth babylon
is fallen it's fallen that great city
happens to be the same institution
that's been attacking christ's ministry
his heavenly sanctuary ministry from
when he was crucified rome attacked him
went into the holy place rome attacked
the most holy place rome is going to
attack right
babylon is fallen's phone innocent does
any man worship the beast and his image
the same shall receive the wrath of god
guess what happens when jesus comes out
of the most holy place
the wrath of god so now we can see how
this message is tied so closely to the
ministry of jesus as he is doing his job
we have to do our job
that's why it's impossible for us to
know what we're going to do if we're not
following the lamb
everywhere he goes i'll let someone else
chime in
praise the lord it really too you know
um
just show the importance of the law of
god in these last days now we look at
the law of god as a transcript of god's
character right it shows us
who jesus is when you really study the
law of god and he's in the most holy
place right now and we're judged by the
law when you read revelation 14 verse 12
there's going to be a people who keep
the commandments of god
that means literally this
they will have jesus living in them the
hope of glory that's the only way
because he keeps the commandments
through you
you have learned to habitually die
in every thought deed and action you
lean upon christ before you think you
lean upon him that's why the bible says
he has to take captive every single
thought that exalts itself against the
knowledge of god and once we become
habitual with letting him take captive
every thought guess what we become
commandment keepers we exude the
character of christ now here's another
way of looking at keeping the
commandments galatians 5 22 and 23 the
fruit of the spirit
when you read when you read the last uh
uh and it says a meekness against such
there is no law you know what that means
that means if christ's character is
manifested in you
that's what it means to keep the law
is to demonstrate the character of
christ how could that be done i am
crucified with christ nevertheless i
live yet not i but christ lives in me
you got to learn how to die habitually
not my will but thine and everything
that we do
this is the work of the most holy place
where christ is saying no no no no trust
me no no no no trust me no no no no
trust me in everything that we do and
there will be a people who learn to
trust him who cooperate with him and
that's why his glory will shine in their
lives at the character of god the ten
commandments will be seen on this earth
and it's the character of jesus that
draws others and that's how they're
gonna come out of babylon when we learn
to submit
every single moment of our lives
to our high priest
so i don't think that's what i intended
to say but that's what just came out of
my mouth so praise the lord praise the
lord the goal
i just want to say one quick thing the
goal of the latter rain and knowing what
time it is and that adam was saying god
wants to prepare people that his
character could shine through us there's
a lot of people who are suffering and
dying it's christmas time they don't
know about the gift of god what god
wants to give to them
and god is going to do his final appeal
to save the world he wants to bring the
harvest in when you look at revelation
14 he's coming on the cloud with a
sickle and god wants to bring the
harvest in so this is the last work of
salvation and god's power is going to be
poured out and this world needs to hear
the message of god's love before he
comes
yeah i want to do uh
i want to do two things here hold on i
think we just lost
that
okay
um i want to talk about the story of
joseph very quickly if i can
um i saw someone asking earlier about an
example in in the bible about judgment
so you remember that joseph's brothers
um
sold them into captivity
right and how many of you remember what
joseph's brothers did to joseph
they
uh
took his coat off
and they
sacrificed and
no no they killed an animal
and dipped his coat in blood
okay
now here's the thing they don't realize
that
in their act of doing that
they were actually
god was securing their salvation
right god was working on their salvation
through this act
so
they go back to their father and tell
them joseph is dead
not realizing that way down the road
right this sending joseph away was going
to actually be for their benefit
jesus death on the cross is going to be
for our benefit amen
right
just as joseph's quote was dipped in
blood symbolizing a sacrifice that
pointed to jesus now
is it is way down towards the end of the
book of genesis that you now find the
brothers
standing before joseph they don't know
it's joseph
joseph has prepared a place for them
but before
he lets them into the place he has
prepared for them he wants to judge them
he wants to see if they have really
changed
and so what does he do
he takes the youngest brother
the least of these his brethren
and he says i want to see how y'all
treat him
because how you treat him
will reflect how you would treat me
the brothers have changed what is it
that changed them i believe
it was their sorrow for what they had
done to their brother
so as they contemplated the pain they
caught their father right as they
contemplated on this
sacrifice
throughout those many years i think it
softened them i think it
it changed their
characters and now
comes the judgment
what happened back then did it really
change you
because you could say one thing and then
when the rubber meets the road yeah
you're just the same person you were you
see what i'm saying
way back along back you know 20 40 50
years ago
but the judgment reveals the fact that
you have changed
this is a snapshot of the entire plan of
salvation
the cross of christ is supposed to bring
in us a sorrow for sin
but the judgment reveals whether it has
really taken root in our hearts
okay that's number one
let me talk saw this question asked like
fifty hundred times i know
i'm looking for it too it's daniel 12
yes okay it's daniel 12
and it's the
1335 the 1290
the 1290 days
the uh
oh i'm sorry there's 260 there's
1295 and then there's
uh 1335.
daniel 12
is basically
checking
you know we talked about checking your
work
daniel 12 is the final
check your work just to make sure that
you got it right right
okay
those three time prophecies
all conclude with 1798 and 1844 or
1843-1844
it is basically another way of checking
the the exact time prophecies we've been
talking about throughout the whole book
of daniel
i will say it again this way
there is only one time prophecy in the
book of daniel it is a 2300 day prophecy
every other time prophecy is a section
of the 2300 days
so the 1335
it leads you to 1843.
the 1295 i mean the 1290 i said 12.95
earlier i meant 12.90 the 1290 leads you
to 1798. the 1260 leads you to 1798.
they all revolve around those two those
two ending points 1798 and 1843 slash
yeah um
i'm going to see if there's any and we
have i guess a few minutes for a couple
of questions or if you guys have some
closing
uh remarks i want to say this before you
uh okay so angela is asking have you
ever have i ever preached or maybe it's
for all of us have you ever preached a
sermon about the ten commandments well
the sermon that i'm gonna be preaching
today
is specifically about the sabbath
and really i'm gonna let you know that
most people
try to get rid of the investigative
judgment
really because of the sabbath
that's really what this boils down to
it's the sabbath the question is does
the sabbath still stand or
has it been done away with
and in this in the sermon coming up um
after this presentation we're just gonna
keep this link open
so i know i have another link out there
but
uh we're just gonna keep this link open
so let people know
um this is the link for the for the the
sermon coming up
text people if you need to let them know
to get on this the the message coming up
today um i am
a defense attorney
and you are the
jury so you have some work to do and and
all i'm asking is that you listen
as an impartial juror to the evidence
just how you would want someone to
listen
on your behalf if you were being accused
of a crime
just as you would want an impartial jury
that's that's your only task
because i'm going to lay out some
information on the sabbath and if you
have ever wanted a video to share
to people you know with people hey
this is
this is why the sabbath still stands
this is going to be that video
all right so
uh that's to answer that question we're
going to be going through a trial scene
regarding the sabbath
excuse me
um
i want to see
if you guys have any closing remarks i
think the question
a couple questions ago that you guys
answered was was beautifully done i mean
just to see the practicality of why this
is
why this we should um how we can apply
this prophecy practically to our lives
every day i'm gonna say again that for
me going through this study with all
three of you
has just been a huge blessing
um because i just i say this every week
but i
jesus is not excluded from this prophecy
this prophecy is about jesus which is
about and even the sanctuary the
sanctuary process is just about christ's
work to save me
and so it just really personalizes
everything and so just again my
encouragement is to everyone
let that be your filter let it like so
view these prophecies and everything in
the bible it is about our salvation it's
about
god trying to save us it's not about him
trying to hurt us it's not because he's
angry or he's mad at us he just wants us
to be saved and he wants us to
understand the things that he wants us
to understand so clearly so that we're
not deceived to believe um something
false but
just always know that his love is the
purpose and the meaning for everything
that he does in the bible but especially
his prophecies and this prophecy so it's
really a beautiful loving thing and if
you guys have any closing remarks guys
yeah amen to that to say i can't i
couldn't have said it any better than
you just said it um
i just praise god for demonstrating his
patient love towards us all
i also want to take a little time just
to thank everybody especially those who
are not in agreeance with what we've
been teaching but you're still showing
up in the chat you're still
throwing out your questions i just want
to take the time to say thank you for
for being here asking your questions
um at the end of the day let's pray for
each other um let's continue to treat
each other with patience and love as our
high priest treats us i just wanted to
take that time to just say you're
appreciated
um i also want to thank the myers uh for
allowing us to be here and i really
believe that this whole study was god
ordained i know they feel the same way
it was very timely
for all of us especially for me
god has done some miraculous things
through these studies
last but not least i just want to
mention that there's some things that
i'm going to be posting on this youtube
channel that i have it's called sons of
might
s-o-n-s-m-i-g-h-t and i'm going to dive
a little bit deeper
and i love to show pictures i'm a visual
guy so i'm going to have charts and
pictures for those of you who love
pictures i'm going to show daniel 8
historically i know there was some
questions about antiochus i'm going to
really get into the history there so it
may be boring for most and then i'm
going to really talk about the judgment
theme in the book of daniel
and there's a couple other things i
might touch on daniel 12 as well so uh
feel free to explore that if you love
pictures and slides to help your
understanding with things but uh praise
god for this whole session
can you give us that that link again
yeah the channel can you give us the
link yeah it's called sons of might
s-o-n-s
and might m-i-g-h-t
sons of might so if you type that up
you'll see
the channel it's like a shield with two
swords
um with a lion on the shield
so you'll see that again it's called
sons of might s-o-n-s
and m-i-g-h-t i'm probably by the grace
of god going to upload a couple videos
especially on daniel
today or tomorrow so praise the lord
that's amazing that's great if you type
it in the chat i think it'll be
other people can catch it if they missed
it
um and it's like so i didn't know you
were doing this but i don't know if you
saw the comment but somebody said the
patel brothers need their own youtube
channel uh to share these things and you
just said it so praise god
tara if you have any closing remarks
yeah i just want to just echo my
brother's statements i'm just grateful
very humbled and honored to be here
it's been a great time of learning and
as i've said before i'm growing in my
understanding
continue to pray for us we pray for you
and uh just keep a tight hold on god's
word and uh god will keep a tight hold
on you and um i'm thankful because god
who wrote this book is powerful enough
to transform lives
and i look at my brother's life i know
where he was and we've heard pastor
mary's testimony
and what gets me excited is that i'm
talking with my brothers
knowing where these guys came from
and seeing where we are today breaking
bread
to me is this the most moving thing
because it's not just cool knowledge
it's the power of the gospel and it's
changed our lives it's given us hope and
it's filled our lives with love joy and
peace and we're so grateful to god for
his power so i want to invite everybody
to just pick up your bible
and give your heart to the author of the
scriptures because he can change your
life too thank you so much uh myers
family love to guide you and i want to
just invite everybody tune in to today's
sermon i'm looking forward to what
pastor power is going to uh bring bread
with us today up sabbath blessing
we love you guys too and thank you both
of you again we i my husband asked you
guys to do this for one week it ended up
being eight weeks so that's pretty cool
we gotta spend two months wow you lose
two months
yeah this was amazing and i'm you know
i'm prophesying this um that we're going
to bring you guys back we're going to
cover other topics um so we'll just have
to pray and see in which way the god
leads um on what topics to bring you
guys back but i know people enjoy the
conversation and how you guys dialogue
and work together so we're definitely
gonna
have you back um but just thank you for
for dedicating two months of your life
because for those of you who don't know
pastor preaches in his at his own church
in idaho he has several churches but he
preaches and then he jumps on that's why
he comes on like 30 minutes late so
that's dedication so we're just thankful
thankful that um your wife let you do
all this
while she's taking care of the kids
so
we are going to oh just another thing
really quick um for those that are yeah
yeah we're going to keep this link open
so you don't have to go anywhere we're
going to take about a five minute break
um so you can just do what you have to
do for five minutes and then we'll be
back on for the beginning of the divine
worship service
um and um we just look forward to seeing
you there so we're gonna go ahead and uh
mute our screen
and our microphone as well
and our microphone as well and then
we'll be back in five minutes so so just
stay tuned
um
sermon coming up the the retrial and by
the way i'm gonna be doing this for
several different topics okay
so we're going on trial um we're looking
at these things in one message we're
going to deal with some uh evidence that
shows that what
prosecutors around the world have said
about the sabbath
is not true
i see some of you making some comments
about some prosecutors who have been on
youtube lately prosecuting the sabbath
so we're gonna look at the counter
evidence and we're just gonna ask the
jurors to
uh be impartial and take a look at the
evidence
your verdict makes all the difference in
the world so sabbath is only the first
one we're going to be dealing with the
state of the dead and
the sanctuary and
hellfire and all of those things so this
is called the retrial
series because we're putting these
things back on trial and seeing is the
sabbath really guilty of being a false
teaching
amen looking forward to it so
let's close in prayer and um
uh pastor ted would you would you close
us out in prayer
absolutely
father we're just so grateful lord for
your mercy your love
your long suffering the power of your
word and your spirit to guide us into
all truth
lord may this not be the end but only
the beginning beginning not only of our
knowledge
but the beginning of our relationship
that it will grow more sweeter and
sweeter with you
lord that you would transform and change
our lives that your character would be
um in us and that you would write your
laws on our hearts bless us for the rest
of the sabbath lord uh bless pastor
marge as he presents the word and bless
all those who would be listening and we
pray lord for your spirit to lead and
guide thank you for all the gifts that
you give to us
especially the gift of your son we thank
you in jesus name amen
fact everyone be right back
you